there's a continuum between the kinds of
cognitive machinery that's at work in
something like insight problem-solving
like when we are having a farm moment
and then that machinery is taken up and
extended into something like what people
call the flow experience so we can talk
about each one of these in more details
as we go along and then in turn that the
machinery the flow experience is
extended and exacted up into mystical
experiences and then that machinery is
in turn can sometimes have an impact on
people in which they seek to transform
the structure of their identity the
structure of their lives and that's a
transformative experience and then when
that intern is making available a set of
practices and skills and virtues that
allows people to address the perennial
problems that beset human beings
problems of self-deception and
self-destructive behavior then we're are
giving at least that that's at least a
good operational definition of what it
is to have achieved enlightenment and so
in a sense right what you're seeing is
the same machinery being recursively
exact it and expanded and complexified
and so there's a continuum and what that
means is we can take some of the
mystique that has been typically
associated with things like
enlightenment or even with mystical
experiences or awakening experiences and
by putting it on a continuum with this
machinery that's more readily understood
and studied within cognitive psychology
and cognitive science we can bring a
deeper understanding which of course
affords both you know better science but
we also are going to emphasize in the
book how that deeper understanding
affords enhancing people's ability to
practice a well basically a course of
the cultivation of wisdom and
enlightenment